# LAUREN TOZZI | Full-Stack Developer

Philadelphia | (954) 258-5028 | laurentozzi.code@gmail.com | linkedin.com/in/laurenreneetozzi | github.com/Ooh-LaLa

#### **Brand Statement**

Having been a stenographer for over a decade, I've been exposed to a surplus of intriguing personal stories which have ultimately inspired me to elevate my goals and create a fresh and impactful transcript of my own. As I transition into the field of software development, I'm thrilled about tackling a new discipline as well as delving into a workspace full of brainpower and problem-solving. I'm a forever-learner who will never cease to be amazed about all there is yet to be discovered in life and computer science.

#### **Skills**

Languages - JavaScript, HTML, CSS, Mongo, JSON, Typescript, EJS

**Database** - MongoDB | **Other** - RESTful Routing, JSON api

Libraries and Frameworks - React (class-based and hooks), Express.js, Tailspin

# **Software Development Projects**

**NOVEMBER 2022 - PRESENT** 

Events - Agenda Application

- Made RESTful API fetch calls **to** an Express, MongoDB, Node.js back-end, handling all create, read, update, delete (CRUD) operations and tested all back-end routes during development using Postman.
- Used Mongoose to define schemas for MongoDB collections.
- Implemented ES6 tagged template literals with Styled-Components along CSS3 to provide style and flexbox layout

#### Hot Slots - Slot Machine Application

- Leveraged embedded Javascript, Javascript, CSS and HTML5, with partials to organize and display the visual aspects
- Wireframed and planned UI design of application using Whimsical
- Utilized Git control during the production of the application with frequent commits until deployment.
- Implemented Javascript methods and functions in order to utilize an Express, MongoDB, and Node.js back-end, creating a representational state transfer(REST)ful application program interface(API).

# **Professional Experience**

Freelance Court Reporter | South Florida - Greater Boston Area

2009 - 2022

- Created transcripts word-for-word using computer-aided equipment.
- Certified transcripts of court proceedings per state and appellate requirements.
- Ability to handle exhibits and keep confidential information.
- Exceptional communication, grammar and editing skills.
- Thorough understanding of legal, English and medical terminology.
- Superior attention to detail and accuracy.

Scheduler | Esquire Deposition Solutions | Ft. Lauderdale, Florida

2007 - 2008

 Managed large call volumes for the accommodation of litigation support and related services for a multitude of law firms, as well as performing extensive data entry.

Legal Secretary | Rakusin Law Firm | Ft. Lauderdale, Florida

2006 - 2007

 Orchestrated hands-on litigation preparation in conjunction with cooperative efforts necessary to produce team-focused results in a demanding environment.

## **EDUCATION**

# **General Assembly | Remote**

NOVEMBER 2022 - MARCH 2023

## **Software Engineering Immersive**

Full-stack software engineering immersive program involving an intensive, 24-week, 450+ hour program, focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling and team-collaboration strategies. Developed a portfolio of individual and group projects.

Massachusetts Bay Community College | Wellesley , Massachusetts

2014 - 2017

**Associate of Science** - General Studies

Sheridan Technical College | Hollywood, Florida

2005 - 2008

**Court Reporting** - Registered Professional Reporter